魅了の魔術
Charm magic.
悪いが　持って生まれた呪いのようなものでな
My apologies.
It's a curse I was born with.
I'm afraid there's nothing I can do about it.
こればかりは如何ともしがたい
俺の出生か　もしくは女に生まれた自分を恨んでくれ
You can blame my birth or the fact that you were born a woman.
Surely you aren't expecting your pretty face to save you from my blade, spear-wielder.
その結構な面構えで
よもや私の剣が鈍るものと期待してはいるまいな
槍使い
そうなっていたら興醒めも甚だしいが
It would be quite the killjoy if it did.
なるほど　セイバークラスの抗魔力は伊達ではないか
I see.
The anti-magic skill of a Saber-class Servant is no fairy tale.
結構
Very well.
この顔のせいで腰の抜けた女を斬るのでは
Cutting down a woman softened by my face would only soil my reputation, anyway.
俺の面目に関わる
最初の一人が骨のある奴で嬉しいぞ
I'm glad my very first opponent is one of mettle.
Oh? So you desire a fair fight.
ほう　尋常な勝負を所望であったか
誇り高い英霊と相見えたのは
I consider myself fortunate to encounter such a proud Heroic Spirit.
私にとっても幸いだ
それでは
Well then...
...let us begin.
いざ
It begins.
始まってるな
誰かが結界を張っている
Someone has put up a magic field.
It's probably the Master of the enemy Servant.
おそらくは敵サーヴァントのマスターだろう
We can observe the entire battlefield from up there.
あの上からなら　戦場がくまなく隅々まで見渡せますが
Indeed, that's a perfect vantage point.
たしかに　監視にはあそこが絶好だ
But anyone who saw it would think so, too.
誰が見たってそう思うだろう
Maiya, you approach from the eastern wharf.
舞弥は東側の岸壁から回り込め
僕は西側から行く。
I'll take the west.
We'll find points where we can monitor both Saber's battle and that crane.
セイバーたちの戦闘と
それとあのデリッククレーンの両方を見張れるポイントに着くんだ
わかりました
Understood.
では　お手並み拝見だ
Let's see what you can do, adorable King of Knights.
かわいい騎士王さん
Utw
Presents
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
Saber is looking out for both spears simultaneously.
セイバーは二本の槍を同時に警戒してるんだわ
She doesn't know which of Lancer's spears is his trump card.
ランサーの切り札はどちらの槍か分からないから
The long spear in his right hand, and the short spear in his left.
右の長槍　左の短槍
Which of those is his Noble Phantasm?
果たしてどちらが宝具なのか
If I can ascertain which, I can make my attack.
それを見極めることができれば
勝負のかけようもあるというものだが
If only we knew his true name.
せめて　真名さえ分かればいいんだけど
He's definitely a Heroic Spirit skilled in the use of spears.
相当な槍使いの英霊であることは間違いない
But that will not suffice.
しかし　それだけでは
What's wrong, Saber? You're on the defensive!
どうしたセイバー　攻めが甘いぞ
He's good.
この男　できる
Curse that sword of hers.
何とまた卦体な剣を
I can't judge my distances without knowing that blade's length.
刀身の長さがわからなければ　間合いの計りようがない
She must be a master swordsman to be able to repel my strikes like that.
こうも我が槍の刃を打ち返すとは
この女　手だれの剣士だ
Maiya.
舞弥
Northeast of Saber and Lancer.
セイバーたちの北東方向
On the roof of that warehouse.
倉庫の屋根の上にランサーのマスターがいる
It's Lancer's Master. Can you see him?
見えるか
Negative. Not from my position.
いいえ　私の位置からは死角のようです
Okay. I'll take him out.
わかった　こちらで仕留める
Assassin?
アサシン
There's activity at the warehouses at the Mion River mouth.
未遠川河口の倉庫街で　動きがありました
The first battle has finally begun.
いよいよ最初の戦闘が始まったようです
Not the first.
最初という言い分はあるまい。
This is technically the second battle, Kirei.
公式には「第二戦」だよ　綺礼
It appears that Saber and Lancer are the combatants.
戦っているのは　どうやら　セイバー
それにランサーのようです
Can you read the Servants' statuses through Assassin's eyes?
アサシンの目からでもサーヴァントステータスは読み取れるか
Easily.
問題なく
Saber's parameters are particularly high.
とりわけセイバーは能力値に恵まれています
Most of them appear to be ranked A.
大方のパラメーターがＡランク相当と見受けます
I see.
なるほどな
She is the strongest Servant class, after all.
さすがは最強クラスといったところか
Saber appears to be a bigger threat than Lancer.
ランサーよりセイバーの方が厄介そうだな
Can you see either Master?
マスターは視認できるか
Other than the Servants, there's only one person who isn't concealed.
堂々と姿を晒しているのは　サーヴァント以外では一人だけ
She's standing behind Saber.
セイバーの背後に控えています
A woman with silver hair.
銀髪の女です
Well, that means Lancer's Master has the wisdom to remain hidden.
ならばランサーのマスターには身を隠すだけの知恵がある　と
He's no novice.
素人ではないな
He understands the rules of the Holy Grail War.
この聖杯戦争の鉄則を弁えている
Wait, a silver-haired woman?
待て　銀髪の女だと
Yes. Caucasian.
はい　白人の女です
With silver hair and red eyes.
銀髪に赤い瞳
She almost doesn't look human.
どうにも人間離れした風情に見えますが
An Einzbern homunculus?
アインツベルンのホムンクルスか
So they created yet another artificial Master.
またしても人形のマスターを鋳造したのか
And I thought Emiya Kiritsugu was the
only pawn Jubstacheit had in store for us.
ユーブスタクハイトが用意した駒は衛宮切嗣だとばかり思っていたが
It appears I was wrong.
まさか見込みが外れるとはな
That woman is the Einzbern Master, then?
ではあの女が　アインツベルンのマスターなのですか
Either way, she'll heavily influence the outcome of the Grail War.
ともかく　その女は聖杯戦争の趨勢を握る重要な鍵だ
Kirei, keep an eye on her.
綺礼　決して目を離すな
Understood.
了解しました
I shall keep one of them on her at all times.
では常時　一人を付けておくことにします
I can see him.
こちらも視認しました
But shouldn't Assassin be dead?
ですが　どうして死んだはずのアサシンが
I knew something was amiss.
やはり裏があったな
Let's see how this plays out for now.
このまま一先ず様子を見よう
Continue to observe Assassin.
引き続きアサシンを監視してくれ
I'll watch Lancer.
僕はランサーを見張る
I'll attack Assassin and draw his attention, so you can use the chance to take down Lancer's Master.
私がアサシンに攻撃を仕掛けて注意を引き付けているその隙に
ランサーのマスターを
No, Maiya.
駄目だ　舞弥
Not when it's Assassin we're dealing with.
あそこに陣取ったのがアサシンだということが問題だ
We aren't prepared to fight Servants right now.
いま我々には対サーヴァント戦の備えがない
Understood.
わかりました
While there is no honor in a battle
fought without an exchange of names,
名乗りもないままの戦いに　名誉も糞もあるまいが
allow me to offer my regards.
ともかく　賞賛を受け取れ
It is impressive for a woman to fight this much without even breaking a sweat.
ここに至って汗一つかかんとは
女だてらに見上げた奴だ
You need not be so humble, Lancer.
無用な謙遜だぞ　ランサー
Even without knowing your name, words from such a master of the spear do me honor.
貴殿の名を知らぬとはいえ
その槍捌きをもってその賛辞
私には誉れだ
I accept them gratefully.
ありがたく頂戴しよう
That's enough fun, Lancer.
戯れ合いはそこまでだ　ランサー
Lancer's Master?
ランサーの　マスター
Do not allow this battle to drag out.
これ以上　勝負を長引かせるな
Saber is a formidable opponent.
そこのセイバーは難敵だ　速やかに始末しろ
Defeat her with all haste.
You may use your Noble Phantasm.
宝具の開帳を許す
Understood, my lord.
了解した　我が主よ
So the long spear is his Noble Phantasm.
あの長槍の方が　ランサーの宝具
That's right.
そういう訳だ
I shall go for the kill now.
ここから先は殺りに行かせてもらう
Saber, you're still using mana to conceal your blade with wind?
セイバー　お前は束ねた風の魔力で剣を隠したままか
I see.
なるほど
So you have a reason to hide your sword.
剣を覆い隠しておきた理由が　お前にはあるということか
My guess is that the sword reveals your true name.
お前の真名
その剣にあると見た
How unfortunate, Lancer.
残念だな　ランサー
You will never know the name of my blade.
貴殿が我が宝剣の正体を知ることはない
I will finish this before then.
その前に勝負を決めて見せる
We'll see about that.
それはどうかな
見えない剣を暴かせてもらうぞ
I shall expose your invisible sword, Saber.
セイバー
Your cherished sword has been exposed.
晒したな　秘蔵の剣を
The Invisible Air was dispelled?!
風王結界が　ほつれだ
What's happening?
何が起こっているの
That red spear is chipping away at the Invisible Air!
あの赤い槍
風王結界を削っている
I now know the exact length of your blade.
刃渡りも確かに見て取った
Now I won't misjudge my distances again!
これでもう 見えぬ間合いに惑わされることはない
I still have a way to counter that spear, however.
だが この槍の筋ならば
まだ応じようもある
If I can just take advantage of...
甘い一撃を
...a brash attack...
見逃さなければ
セイバー
Saber!
Thank you, Irisviel.
ありがとう アイリスフィール
I'm fine. The healing was effective.
大丈夫 治癒は効いています
So, you just won't let me win that easily.
やはり 易々と勝ちを獲らせてはくれんか
But why?
だが 何故
My armor should have easily deflected that strike.
あの一撃なら 充分に鎧で防げたはず
So how did that blade...
なのに 何故 槍の刃が
The armor itself wasn't pierced.
鎧に傷がない
What's going on here?
どういう事だ
The only explanation is that Lancer's blade went through my magically woven armor.
ランサーの槍が
魔力で編む鎧を通り抜けたとしか
So that's it.
そうか その槍の秘密が見えてきたぞ ランサー
I see the secret of your spear, Lancer.
That red spear cancels mana.
その赤い槍は魔力を断つのだな
And your armor was created with mana.
その甲冑は魔力で生成されたもの
You should just surrender if you're relying on it, Saber.
それを頼みにしていたのなら
諦めるのだな セイバー
You're as good as naked before my spear.
俺の槍の前では丸裸も同然だ
Don't think that you've won simply by depriving me of my armor.
たかだか鎧を剥いだぐらいで
得意になってもらっては困る
If I cannot defend against your blade, I only need to cut you down first.
防ぎ得ぬ槍ならば 防ぐより先に斬るまでのこと
Prepare yourself, Lancer!
覚悟してもらおう ランサー
So you're going all out.
思い切ったものだな
You're betting everything on one strike.
乾坤一擲 ときたか
You're converting the disadvantages of having the
armor to the advantages gained from abandoning it.
鎧を奪われたことの不利を
鎧を捨てることの利点で覆す
What courage. What a bold decision.
その勇敢さ 潔い決断
I like that.
決して嫌いではないがな
But it is a foolish mistake in this case, Saber.
この場に限って言わせてもらえば
それは失策だったぞ セイバー
We shall see.
さて どうだか
You can continue remonstrating after my next attack.
諌言は 次の打ち込みを受けてからにしてもらおうか
I'm telling you, that's a mistake.
それは失策だったぞ
Servants can have more than one Noble Phantasm...
宝具は決して単一とは限らない
A trap?!
罠か
This is bad. Very bad.
いかんなあ これはいかん
Wh-What is?
な 何がだよ
Lancer just unleashed his finishing move.
ランサーの奴め
決め技に訴えおった
He wants to end the battle right there.
早々に勝負を決める気だ
And isn't that better for us?
いや それって好都合なんじゃ
Fool! What are you talking about?
馬鹿者 何を言っとるか
I wanted to keep watching until a few more Masters showed up,
もう何人か出揃うまで様子を見たかったのだが
but Saber might be defeated at this rate.
あのままではセイバーが脱落しかねん
Then it will be too late.
そうなってからでは遅い
T-Too late?
お お 遅いって
Wasn't the plan to attack after they've knocked each other out?
奴らが潰し合うのを待ってから襲う計画だったんじゃないか
It's true that I was hoping other Servants would answer Lancer's challenge.
たしかに余は他のサーヴァントがランサーの挑発に乗って
出てこないものかと期待しておった
Isn't it obvious?
当然であろう
It would be faster to fight them all at once than have to find them one by one.
一人ずつ捜し出すよりも
まとめて相手にした方が手っ取り早いではないか
All at once?
まとめて 相手
Yes.
応とも
Rarely does one have the chance to exchange blows with heroes from another age.
異なる時代の英雄豪傑と矛を交える機会など滅多にない
And if six of them gathered in one place, I'd get to fight all of them.
それが六人も揃うとなれば
一人たりとも逃す手はあるまい
Look at Saber and Lancer.
現に セイバーとランサー
Both are valiant warriors I would love to duel with.
あの二人にしてからが
ともに胸の熱くなるような益荒男だ
It'd be a pity to let either die.
死なすには惜しい
死なさないでどーすんのさ
But isn't that the point?!
You're supposed to kill each other in the Holy Grail War!
聖杯戦争は殺し合いだってば
To win, but not destroy...
勝利してなお滅ぼさぬ 制覇してなお辱めぬ
To conquer, but not humiliate...
That is what true conquest is!
それこそが真の「征服」である
We watch no longer!
見物はここまでだ
We shall also participate, boy!
我らも参じるぞ 坊主
You idiot!
馬鹿馬鹿馬鹿
What you're doing is insane!
オマエやってること出鱈目だ
You can stay here and watch if you don't approve.
気に食わぬなら
この場所に残って見ているか
I'll go!
行きます 連れて行け馬鹿
Take me, you idiot!
Good! Now that's my Master!
良し それでこそ我がマスター
まずいことに腱を切られた
This is bad. He severed a tendon.
I can't move my thumb.
親指が動かない
You just won't let me win.
つくづく すんなり勝たせてはくれんのか
Still, I admire your persistence!
良いがな その不屈ぶりは
何を悠長なことを言っている
What are you talking so much for, you fool?
バカめ  仕留め損ねおって
You missed the chance to defeat her.
痛み入る  我が主よ
I apologize, my lord.
Irisviel.
アイリスフィール 私にも治癒を
Heal me as well.
But I have...
かけたわ かけたのに そんな
I have, and yet...
治癒は間違いなく効いているはずよ
I healed you. It should've worked.
Saber, you should already be fully healed!
セイバー あなたは今の状態で完治しているはずなの
You did well to realize your armor
was useless before my Gae Dearg.
我が「破魔の紅薔薇」を前にして
鎧が無為だと悟ったまでは良かったな
But it was rash of you to abandon your armor.
が 鎧を捨てたのは早計だった
そうでなければ
Had you not done so, you could've guarded against my Gae Buidhe.
「必滅の黄薔薇」は防げていたものを
成る程 一度穿てば
I see.
A cursed spear that inflicts wounds that will not heal.
その傷を決して癒さぬという呪いの槍
I should have realized this sooner.
もっと早くに気付くべきだった
A red spear that negates magic, a cursed yellow spear,
魔を断つ赤槍 呪いの黄槍
and a mole that enchants women beneath the right eye.
加えて 乙女を惑わす右目の泣き黒子
First of the knights of Fianna, Diarmuid of the Radiant Face.
フィオナ騎士団 随一の戦士
「輝く貌」のディルムッド
まさか手合わせの栄に与るとは思いませんでした
I never dreamed that I would have the honor of facing you.
それがこの聖杯戦争の妙であろうな
It's all thanks to the Holy Grail War.
だがな 誉れ高いのは俺の方だ
But it is me who is honored here.
No Heroic Spirit summoned by the Holy Grail could ever mistake that golden blade.
時空を越えて「英霊の座」にまで招かれた者ならば
その黄金の宝剣を見違えはせぬ
To face the legendary King of Knights and land even a single blow...
かの名高き騎士王と鍔競り合って
一矢報いるまでに到ったとは
どうやらこの俺も捨てたものではないらしい
I must be pretty skilled myself.
Now that we both know each other's names, we can duel honorably, as knights.
さて 互いの名も知れたところで
ようやく騎士として尋常なる勝負を挑めるわけだが
Or are you upset that this is happening after you've lost an arm, Saber?
それとも 片腕を奪われた後では不満かな セイバー
戯れ事を
Don't be ridiculous.
It's humiliating that you would be concerned over such a scratch.
この程度の手傷に気兼ねされたのでは むしろ屈辱だ
Prepare yourself, Saber.
覚悟しろ　セイバー
I'll get you this time.
次こそは獲る
Only if I don't get you first, Lancer.
それは私に獲られなかった時の話だぞ ランサー
A chariot?!
戦車
Both of you, sheathe your blades.
双方 剣を収めよ
You are in the presence of a king!
王の前であるぞ
I am Iskandar, King of Conquerors!
我が名は征服王イスカンダル
此度の聖杯戦争においては　ライダーのクラスを得て現界した
I am of the Rider class in this Grail War.
Episode 4
Blade of the Demonic Spear
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
I am Iskandar, King of Conquerors!
我が名は征服王イスカンダル
ステータスも何も全然読めない
I can't read its status or anything else about it!
Irisviel, stand back!
アイリスフィール 下がって
That is his Noble Phantasm.
あれが 奴の宝具
With this Command Spell, I order you...
令呪をもって命じる
Believe in your Master!
あなたのマスターを信じて
She has been revived at last!
ついに復活を遂げた
Nothing will remain of your corpse!
もはや肉片一つも残さぬぞ
Next Episode
Howl of a Mad Beast